Raymond Selent

Data Scientist

Fast-learning, gritty, curious Data Professional with strong Python, analytical, and visualization skills. Bringing communication, teamwork, and customer service skills from 10 years in IT consultancy, as well as a bold, creative approach to problem solving honed from studies in theatre.

rselent@ufl.edu 954-990-3121 Fort Lauderdale, FL rselent.github.io linkedin.com/in/rselent github.com/rselent

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Data Science

Lambda School of Computer Science and Web Development

11/2019 - 08/2020 Remote

- 9-month Academy: Python, SQL, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Predictive Modeling, Neural Networks
- 1400+ hours of coding experience
- CodeSignal GCA Score: 651

Theatre

University of Florida

08/2014 - 06/2018 Gainesville, FL

Additional Coursework: C, Python

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Dramaturg

UF School of Theatre + Dance

01/2018 - 05/2018

- Self-organized contextual research & analysis of Restoration comedy The Beaux' Stratagem
- Supported and empowered a team of 24+ cast & crew members, being both a controlled source of information and relieving cast & crew of research burdens
- Triaged questions and communicated answers, research findings, insights, and notes during daily production meetings & rehearsals

Virtual Chief Information OfficerConsultant

02/2006 - 07/2016

- Partnered with business leaders and took ownership of all processes, successes, & failures
- Interviewed owners & employees to understand IT challenges and identify root causes
- Recommended & executed forward-looking actions to strengthen connections between IT and business objectives
- Solved growing internal organizational blockers by self-teaching Python and developing custom CRM system, automating customer tracking tasks

SKILLS



DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Software Engineer — Schrödinger's Server (01/2021)

- Developed interactive command-line utility that reports whether a domain's web server is reachable or not
- Implemented checks to verify user input
- Built with Python within 3 days, using 1 library, and with no prior library knowledge / experience

Data Scientist / Engineer — Project Canopy (03/2020 - 05/2020)

- Led & advocated for 4-person Data team inside 14-member cross-functional Project team: established roadmaps, tracked KPIs with Project Lead, and reassessed milestones when needed
- Collaborated with Stakeholders and Frontend, Backend, and UX teams to create desired reporting dashboard & continually improve user experience within 8-week project timeline
- Architected & built custom ETL pipeline: identified 20 external APIs & data sources, extracted & cleaned data, designed database structure, and warehoused data in secure Amazon-hosted PostgreSQL database
- Exploited observed gaps in cross-sectional data to predict future events, fulfilling special product request

Machine Learning Engineer — P-H-A Assistant (01/2020)

- Built, evaluated, A/B tested, and debugged multiple prediction models within 2 days, using logistic regression, random forest, perceptron, CatBoost, and LightGBM algorithms
- Deployed best-performant prediction model to Heroku-hosted web app inside another 2 days (4 total) while self-teaching needed technologies like Flask, Plotly, and Heroku

Data Analyst — Airbnb Insights in NYC (11/2019)

- Sourced, cleaned, and analyzed 48,000-observation dataset of Airbnb listings in all 5 boroughs of New York City
- Created custom visualizations with Seaborn library, supporting and amplifying insights, analyses, and recommendations
- Discovered and investigated innocent-looking data points, uncovering potentially unlawful behaviour